AGATA (TALITA) ANDRZEJEWSKA

Software Engineer

📞 66500180 🛛 agatamonikaandrzejewska@gmail.com github.io/talitadzikzlasu Ocopenhagen, Denmark

SUMMARY

I'm a full-stack developer who's been in the game for over 7 years, and I still love diving into code every day. I love working with React, Node.js, or TypeScript, I'm always aiming to write clean, elegant code that makes life easier for developers (and future me!). I've built everything from large-scale social platforms to quirky open-source projects, and I thrive on solving tough problems while always learning something new. I'm all about creating intuitive Uls and solid back-end architectures that just work beautifully.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer

01/2024 - Present

Vivino

Copenhagen, Denmark

- Independently developed and enhanced new features for the Vivino web shop, catering to a global user base of 75 million.
- Collaborated closely with designers and product managers to implement intuitive, userfriendly components, ensuring a seamless e-commerce experience.
- Took full ownership of feature development, from planning through to production
- Technologies: TypeScript, React, Ruby on Rails, Jest

Senior Full-stack and Front-end Developer

09/2017 - Present

Toptal

Remote

Sandbox AQ (2022 - 2023)

- Migrated several pages from Ruby on Rails to React, modernizing the architecture and improving front-end performance.
- Ensured that the migrated components were fully integrated with existing systems while maintaining data integrity and security.
- Technologies: React, TypeScript, Ruby on Rails
- **Secureframe** (2021 2022)

Built a comprehensive component library in React and TypeScript, ensuring reusable and scalable UI elements for the platform.

- Worked on creating pixel-perfect components based on Figma designs.
- <u>Technologies</u>: React, TypeScript, Storybook, Figma
- Highlight your accomplishments, using numbers if possible.
- Various Toptal Clients (2017-2021)
- Led the development of multiple full-stack applications in the social platform domain.
- Built full-stack applications using Node.js and React, acting as the main engineer responsible for both front-end and back-end architecture.
- Developed key features such as user authentication, hierarchical comment systems, and scalable REST APIs.
- Focused on building performant, secure, and user-friendly applications, ensuring high code quality through unit testing and best practices.
- Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, React, Redux, PostgreSQL, Docker, AWS

Senior Software Engineer

2021 - 2023

Hnutí Brontosaurus

- Remote Led the **UX design** and development of features for event management, participant
- tracking, and bulk actions Worked in a two-person team of developers, where we built and designed the entire
- internal platform from the ground up, supporting over 20,000 users. Created and implemented key functionalities such as application management and PDF
- document generation. Styled the platform using SCSS, adhering to web accessibility standards, and delivered a
- clean, user-friendly interface. Technologies: React, TypeScript, Redux, Python Django, SCSS.
- github: https://github.com/hnuti-brontosaurus/bis-frontend
- preview: https://www.loom.com/share/3c5ec034b75e44739cabe7ceff62860a



SKILLS

Languages & Frameworks:

JavaScript · TypeScript · React · Node.js ·

Python · Ruby on Rails · Express.js ·

Hapi.js · Redux · Next.js

Front-end:

React · Redux · SCSS · HTML5 ·

Responsive Design · SCSS · Tailwind ·

Styled components

Back-end:

Python · Ruby on Rails · express.is · hapi ·

SQL(PostgreSQL/MySQL) · Docker ·

ArangoDB · REST APIs · OAuth

Tools & Platforms

Git · GitHub · Cypress · Jest · Figma ·

Storybook

Specialized Areas:

UX Design · Performance Optimization ·

Security · Full-stack Architecture ·

Algorithms

EDUCATION



Bachelor's/Master's Studies in Computer Science (Incomplete)

Completed significant coursework toward a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science, focusing on algorithms, software engineering

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance and Open-source Developer

2007 - 2019

Various projects and clients:

Warsaw/Remote

- Web Development: Developed full-stack websites using Python, Django, HTML, and JavaScript. Built REST APIs and relational databases using Node.js and Express.js.
- Ditup.org: Co-founded a platform for connecting individuals with similar interests. Built
 and secured back-end APIs using Node.js and ArangoDB.
- Influenced (Open-source Project): Developed a web app visualizing relationships between influential figures using React, Redux, D3.js, and SPARQL.
- Dictionary and Book Translator: Built a Python application for translating books using graph databases for dictionary storage.
- Steganography-based Communicator: Developed a secure communicator using C++ and Java, focusing on encryption and steganography.